

 [
    {
      "question": " Large farming estates",
      "choice1": "latifundia",
      "choice2": "Pax Romana",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "praetors",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Roman peace ",
      "choice1": "latifundia",
      "choice2": "Pax Romana",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "praetors",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "a ruler with complete control over the country",
      "choice1": "latifundia",
      "choice2": "Pax Romana",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "praetors",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": " government officials who interpreted Roman law and served as judges",
      "choice1": "latifundia",
      "choice2": "Pax Romana",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "praetors",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "government officials who interpret the law and serve as judges",
      "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "an elect official who protects the rights of ordinary citizens",
      "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "A person granted absolute power",
      "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "The idea that citizens have a responsibility to help their country",
     "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "The ____________ was the ruling class on top officials of the Roman Republic",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Rome fought ___________ in the punic wars.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "The ____________ was Rome's first code of laws.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "_____________ was a famous Roman dictator.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "The _____________ went on strike to protest that they had no power in the government.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "plebeians",
      "answer": 4
    },  
  {
      "question": " to reject ",
      "choice1": " veto ",
      "choice2": " legions",
      "choice3": " plebeians",
      "choice4": " trumvirate",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": " small groups of Roman soldiers ",
       "choice1": " veto ",
      "choice2": " legions",
      "choice3": " plebeians",
      "choice4": " trumvirate",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": " the Roman working class",
       "choice1": " veto ",
      "choice2": " legions",
      "choice3": " plebeians",
      "choice4": " trumvirate",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": " a group of three people who share equal political power",
       "choice1": " veto ",
      "choice2": " legions",
      "choice3": " plebeians",
      "choice4": " trumvirate",
      "answer": 4
    },
  {
      "question": " What is the Hagia Sophia ",
      "choice1": " Church ",
      "choice2": " Romulus Augustulus",
      "choice3": " latins",
      "choice4": " Etruscan Wall Paintings",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": " In 476, what emperor was overthrown by Germanic tribes ",
       "choice1": " Church ",
      "choice2": " Romulus Augustulus",
      "choice3": " latins",
      "choice4": " Etruscan Wall Paintings",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": " who were the original settlers of Rome?",
       "choice1": " Church ",
      "choice2": " Romulus Augustulus",
      "choice3": " Etruscans",
      "choice4": " Etruscan Wall Paintings",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": " what is fresco",
        "choice1": " Church ",
      "choice2": " Romulus Augustulus",
      "choice3": " latins",
      "choice4": " Etruscan Wall Paintings",
      "answer": 4
    }
  ]
